Guide to the Blanchard Rideout papers, 1929-1966, [bulk 1959-1966].
Rideout, Blanchard papers, 1929-1966, [bulk 1959-1966].
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Blanchard Rideout papers, 1929-1966, [bulk 1959-1966].
34-8-1033
Blanchard Rideout
5.6 cubic ft.
Correspondence, pamphlets, evaluations, clippings, articles and other materials.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes files involving Peace Corps activities at Cornell,and Blanchard Rideout's role in Frank Rhodes' inaugeration and as marshall for the 1971-1979 commencement ceremonies. Also correspondence with Morris Bishop, and drafts of his memorial statement which Blanchard wrote, including an explanation of the quote found on the memorial plaque to Bishop in Sage Chapel.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes files involving Peace Corps activities at Cornell,and Blanchard Rideout's role in Frank Rhodes' inaugeration and as marshall for the 1971-1979 commencement ceremonies. Also correspondence with Morris Bishop, and drafts of his memorial statement which Blanchard wrote, including an explanation of the quote found on the memorial plaque to Bishop in Sage Chapel.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Rideout, Blanchard.; Bishop, Morris, 1893-1973.; Rhodes, Frank Harold Trevor.; Cornell University--History.; Cornell University--Students.; Peace Corps (U.S.); Sage Chapel (Cornell University)
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Box 5 is restricted.
RELATED MATERIALS
See also Cornell University Banners, Clothing, and Other Textiles, #47-7-3439, for Rideout's graduation regalia.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Cornell Centennial Committee
Series II. Peace Corps (U.S.)
Series III. Photographs
Series IV. Personal
Series V. Restricted Materials
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Cornell Centennial Committee
  - Son et Lumiere, June 15, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Centennial Campaign Booklets, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Centennial Campaign Booklets, 1962-1965 (Box 1)
  - Centennial Campaign Newspaper Clippings, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Performing Arts at Cornell University-Newspaper clippings, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Charter Week-Cornell University, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Cornell Convocation, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - International Student Conference-Cornell University, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Cornell Centennial Committee, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Cornell Centennial Committee, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Cornell Centennial Committee, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Cornell University-Charter Week, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Cornell University-Charter Week, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Cornell University-Charter Week, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Cornell University-Charter Week, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - The Universities and the Arts Lincoln Center for the Performing Arts, Mar. 9-12, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Charter Day Convocation-Cornell University, Apr. 27, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Charter Day Convocation-Cornell University, Apr. 27, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Cornell Convocation, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Series II. Peace Corps (U.S.)
  - Acceptance List, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - American Studies and World Affairs Committee, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Applications for staff positions, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Area Studies, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Assessment-FAO's, 1962-1965 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Book Inventory (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Book Shipment, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Budget Final, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Budget Proposal, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Colorado Conference, Mar. 26-28, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Bus and Taxi, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Commencement, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Coop Training (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Departure from Ithaca, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Equitation Physical Education, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - ETV, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Forestry, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - FSI Ratings, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Health Training-Peru/UCD, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Housing and Dining, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Language Training-Peru/UCD, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - News Release, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Number of Trainees Expected, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Medical Dental Services, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Orientation, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Orientation Days, 1963-1965 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Orientation Course, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Physical Training (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Peace Corps Orientation Course, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Program Description-Peru UCD, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Peace Corp Volunteers correspondence with prospective staff, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Peace Corp Recruiting Instructions, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Schedule of Classes, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Staff Meeting for Peace Corps Training Program, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Technical Skills, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Training Institutions, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Film "A Mission of Discovery, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Health Training, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Health Education, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Peace Corps Inventory of Equipment, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Project for Summer, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Reports, Peace Corps Programs at Cornell, Peru 1962, Sierra Leone 1963, 1962-1964 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Proposal for Tunisia Training Program, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Training Sites, June 1961-Dec. 1964 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - VISTA Office of Economic Opportunity (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Peace Corps Peru RCA Project Syllabuses and Biographies, 1963-1965 (Box 2)
  - Peace Corps Reports, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Financial Report Peru UCD, ETV, Forestry, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Peace Corps Budget, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Advanced Planning Budget, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Monthly Bills Checked and Paid, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Payroll Vouchers, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Stamp and Air Forms, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Monthly Statements, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Correspondence, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Forms for Lecturers (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Salary Recovery Forms (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Psychiatric Interview Forms (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Biography Forms-Faculty (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Peace Corps Health Training Plan for the Health Training Coordinator (Box 2)
  - Speech Material (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Health Training, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Research Notes, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Acceptances for the Peace Corps, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Applicants for appointments, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - American Studies and World Affairs, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Area Studies, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Assessment, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Budget for Peru RCA Peace Corps Programs, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Proposed Budget, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Correspondence, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Correspondence and 104 Program Description, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Evaluation, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Peace Corps report, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Health Training and First Aid, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Housing and Dining (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Invitations (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Language and Training, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Letters concerning selection of Peace Corps Volunteers, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Oklahoma Conference, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Peace Corps Long Range Planning, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - Physical Training, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Peace Corps unanswered mail from volunteers, 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence from Peace Corps volunteers, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Project for summer, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Recruitment, 1963-1965 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Reporting Instructions, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Schedule, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Syllabus, 1962-1964 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Technical Skills, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Teaching English as a Second Language, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Tests-interpretations of scores, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Visitors, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Peace Corps Peru RCA/ Tools Project-Supplement to Preliminary Report, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Peace Corps Addresses Overseas, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Cornell Students in the Peace Corps, 1963-1965 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Peace Corps Speeches, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Peace Corps Staff, Washington D.C., 1962-1964 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Peace Corps Testing, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - College Credit for Peace Corps Courses, 1962-1964 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Peace Corps Volunteers Career Information Services, 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Sierra Leone Peace Corps Training Lists, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Peace Corps newspaper clippings and miscellaneous correspondence, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Peace Corps newspaper clippings, 1962-1965 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Letters from Peace Corps Volunteers, 1962-1965 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Peace Corps letters from Peru, 1962-1965 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Peace Corps Volunteers mail, 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Peace Corps Report Draft, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Miscellaneous Peace Corps Correspondence, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Plans for Peace Corps Training Programs, 1962-1963 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Washington D.C. Trip, June 1-3, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Miscellaneous Peace Corps Correspondence, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Peace Corps, Burma Project, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Peace Corps Pamphlets, 1960's (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Peace Corps Pamphlets, 1960's (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Peace Corps Volunteer newsletters, 1962-1965 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Miscellaneous Peace Corps newsletters, 1960's (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Peace Corps Trainee Information for Peru UCD/Forestry/ETV projects, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Miscellaneous information concerning Peace Corps training, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Peace Corps information concerning appointments, salaries and fees, 1960's (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Peace Corps courses information, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Miscellaneous Peace Corps materials, 19621963 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Subseries A. Administrative Files
    - Peace Corps Bills, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Peru Budget, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Technical Skills, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1962-1963 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Subseries B. Appointments/Financial Files
    - Training Program, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Lecturer letters and Time Sheets, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Peace Corps Peru RCA-samples, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Peace Corps Peru RCA-samples (continued), 1964 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Peace Corps Peru RCA-samples (continued), 1964 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Peace Corps Sierra Leone, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Planning Fall Project-Peru, Bolivia, Ecuador Peace Corps, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Peace Corps Peru III Project-Report, June 14-Aug. 12, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Peace Corps Sierra Leone IV Project-Report, June 17-Aug. 24, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Peace Corps Latin America Regional I Project-syllabus, Sept. 18, 1963-Jan. 31, 1964 (Box 4)
  - Peace Corps Peru RCA Project-syllabus, June 18-Aug. 22, 1964 (Box 4)
  - Peace Corps Peru RCA project-biographies, June 18-Aug. 22, 1964 (Box 4)
  - Peace Corps Peru UCD-Forestry-ETV Projects-biographies, June 19-Sept. 11, 1965 (Box 4)
  - Peace Corps Peru UCD-Forestry-ETV Projects-syllabus, June 19-Sept. 11, 1965 (Box 4)
  - Peace Corps Sierra Leone IV Project-syllabus, June 17-Aug. 24, 1963 (Box 4)
  - Peace Corps Sierra Leone IV Project-biographies, June 17-Aug. 24, 1963 (Box 4)
  - Peace Corps Peru Project-biographies, June 14-Aug. 12, 1962 (Box 4)
  - Peace Corps Peru III Project-syllabus, June 14-Aug. 12, 1962 (Box 4)
  - Peace Corps-The Peace Corps in Peru: The First Months, Sept.-Dec. 1962 (Box 4)
  - Measurement of Peace Corps Program Impact in the Peruvian Andes, May 31, 1963 (Box 4)
  - Cornell Alumni News-article on the Peace Corps, Sept. 1964 (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous Peace Corps newsletters, 1960's (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Peace Corps newsletters, 1960's (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Working Effectively Overseas-a booklet prepared by the Peace Corps (Box 4)
  - Book and film orders, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Peace Corps Sierra Leone training program-commencement exercises, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Payroll forms-samples, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Technical Skills-staff and lecturers payments, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Trainee Stipends, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Native Speakers Language Course, 1963-1964 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Cost of Sierra Leone IV Peace Corps Project (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Final Budget Form, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Sierra Leone Budget, 1962-1963 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Peace Corps-paid bills, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Peace Corps Planning for 1963, 1962-1963 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Budget Proposal for 1963, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Books for use in Sierra Leone, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Road Construction, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Staff List, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous materials, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Cooperative Membership Education, 1962-1963 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - 10 and 104 forms, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - General correspondence, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Housing and Dining, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Jeep materials, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Miscellaneous lawyer information, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - List of Trainees, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Sierra Leone Rural Community Development Project newsletter (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - American Studies and World Affairs, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Student Questionnaires (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - School Construction, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Sierra Leone IV Project-standards for successful completion (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Miscellaneous teacher information, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - General technical skills, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Washington orientation meeting, May 1963 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Visitors and Peace Corps service course, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Water sanitation construction (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Information concerning Peace Corps dropouts, 1959-1965 (Box 4, Folder 38)
- Series III. Photographs
  - Peace Corps Photographs-Cornell Trainees in Peru (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Peace Corps Photographs, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Peace Corps Training, Summer 1962 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Peace Corps Training, Summer 1962 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Peace Corps Volunteers in various countries (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Peace Corps Training Photographs, Aug. 1962 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Miscellaneous photograph (Box 4, Folder 45)
- Series IV. Personal
  - Blanchard Rideout's class book, 1929 (Box 6)
- Series V. Restricted Materials
  - Peace Corps volunteers registration data-A, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Peace Corps volunteers registration data-B, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Peace Corps volunteers registration data-C-D, 1963-1964 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Peace Corps volunteers registration data-E-F, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Peace Corps volunteers registration data-G-H, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Peace Corps volunteers registration data-J-L, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Peace Corps volunteers registration data-M, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Peace Corps volunteers registration data-N-P, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Peace Corps volunteers registration data-R-S, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Peace Corps volunteers registration data-T-W, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Peace Corps Instructors' grades and evaluations-A-B, 1962-1963 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Peace Corps Instructors' grades and evaluations-C-D, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Peace Corps Instructors' grades and evaluations-E-H, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Peace Corps Instructors' grades and evaluations-I-J, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Peace Corps Instructors' grades and evaluations-K-M, 1962-1963 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Peace Corps Instructors' grades and evaluations-N-P, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Peace Corps Instructors' grades and evaluations-R-Si, 1962-1963 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Peace Corps Instructors' grades and evaluations-Sm-V, 1962-1964 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Peace Corps Instructors' grades and evaluations-W, 1962-1964 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Sierra Leone IV project files of Peace Corps volunteers-A-B, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Sierra Leone IV project files of Peace Corps volunteers-C-D, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Sierra Leone IV project files of Peace Corps volunteers-G, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Sierra Leone IV project files of Peace Corps volunteers-H, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Sierra Leone IV project files of Peace Corps volunteers-K-L, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Sierra Leone IV project files of Peace Corps volunteers-M, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Sierra Leone IV project files of Peace Corps volunteers-O-P, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Sierra Leone IV project files of Peace Corps volunteers-R-S, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Sierra Leone IV project files of Peace Corps volunteers-T-W, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Final Report for Sierra Leone Peace Corps, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Peace Corps Trainee grades Peru Program, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Grades, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Peace Corps Peru RCA-project evaluations (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Health and medical records, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Medical materials, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Peace Corps reports on trainees, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Peace Corps evaluations, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Contracts for Peru Peace Corps program, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Contracts for Peru Peace Corps program, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Staff appointments, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Peace Corps contracts, 1964-1965 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Hourly Time Record Forms, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Multiple Payment Lists (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Notices of Termination, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Appointments and payrolls, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Pay vouchers-volunteer stipends, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Appointments and payrolls, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 46)